Gary Tate

86 West Acre, Byram, Knottingley, West Yorkshire, WF11 9DU

Phone: 07411 975 783 - Email: g.tate@me.com
github.com/garytate123 - www.gt-web-dev.site

Introduction

I am currently studying JAMstack Frontend Web Development with The Coders Guild and I've been retaining myself within web development for the past year. I have over 16 years of work experience in the charity sector, managing youth projects and leading teams. For the past four years I have been self-employed as an events coordinator, working with a large international charity, leasing with marketing and engagement teams. I have gained many soft skills and strengths that would benefit many companies and teams. I would describe myself as approachable, friendly & easy to get along with. I'm a creative problem solver that thrives with new challenges and stays calm under pressure. I have a great desire to keep learning, developing and growing both as a person and professionally.

Skills

Primary Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SCSS/SASS, JQuery, Bootstrap4, Git, Github, Eleventy, Nunjucks, API's.

Secondary Web Technologies: React.js, Node.js, Express.js.

Other Skills: Responsive Design, Accessibility.

Actively Learning: PHP, Python, SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, SEO, CMS.

Soft Skills: Motivated, Customer Focus, Communication, Creative, Self-Starter, Calm Under Pressure, Reliable, Timekeeping, Team player, Life long learner.

Training

The Coders Guild: JAMstack Bootcamp, 2 month pre-apprenticeship course

UDEMY: The App Brewery - The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp, **RefactorU LLC** - Getting Started as a Web Developer, Git with Visual Studio Code and Command Line Git.

FreeCodeCamp - Responsive Web Design Certification.

References

Work:

Darren Richards, Head of Engagement, Mercy Ships 12 Meadway Court, Stevenage, SG1 2EF, Email: darren.richards@mercyships.org.uk Phone: 07591 203 586

Character:

Geoff Baxter (OBE) Email: gb@geoffbaxterconsultancy.com Phone: 07743 780 713

Gary Tate - Phone: 07411 975 783 - Email: g.tate@me.com

Education

September 2013 Oasis College,

Mentoring Through Intentional Relationships

PASS

September 2003 - 2005 Sunderland University,

JNC Community & Youth Work

National Diploma PASS

September 2002 Newcastle College, HEFC English Language

PASS

September 1996 - 1997 Sherburn High School 6th Form,

GNVQ Intermediate Science

PASS

September 1991 - 1997 Sherburn High School, GCSE's

Art & Design, Biology, Chemistry, Physics, RE, English,

Mathematics.

Work Experience

Sep 2016 - PRESENT Freelance

Event Coordinator

Main duties: Coordinate conferences & events for Mercy Ships. Recruit, train & manage volunteers for representing Mercy Ships at conferences & large festivals. Provide administration tasks, logistics and liaise with the marketing & engagement teams to ensure clear targets and outcomes for each event .

Sep2012 - Sep 2016 Moortown Baptist Church

Youth Worker

Main duties: Lead all aspects of the church's youth work, Recruit, manage & train over 25 volunteers, Develop & grow the youth work program. Plan & deliver regular youth groups, cell groups & youth services. Design and develop a website. Organise youth residentials & one-off events. Pastoral care of young people. Network & partner with organisations & churches.

Aug 2012 - Sep 2015 Leeds Faith in Schools

Schools Worker (SECONDMENT FROM MOORTOWN BAPTIST CHURCH)

Main duties: Plan & deliver lessons, assemblies & lunch-time group. Mentor young people in a one to one and a group setting.

Work Experience

Sep 2008 - Aug 2012 Contagious Youth Project Project Coordinator

Main duties: To coordinate all aspects of schools and youth work of the project. Recruit & manage volunteers, gap year students and lead team meetings. Plan and deliver assemblies, school lessons, small groups, youth groups, lunch-time clubs. Mentoring, one to one support within the school pastoral team. Design and develop a website. Develop the charities work amongst schools, young people, the local community and report to the Board of Trustees

Sep 2006 - Sepr 2008 Acorn Community Church
Youth Development Worker (Part-time)

Main duties: To oversee all aspects of youth work within the church. To plan and run discipleship groups, youth clubs & workshops. To organise one-off events & youth residentials To recruit and coordinate a team of youth work volunteers.

Sep 2006 - Sep 2008 YMCA Youth & Children's Worker

Main duties: To support the children's and youth work program. Plan and run after school youth clubs. Keep an up to date register and evaluation forms. Co-coordinate a 'Ten Sing' performing arts group. Plan and run drama and music production workshops.

Sep 2005 - Sep 2006 Community Regeneration Trust
After School Club Manager

Main duties: To manage all aspects of the after-school club. To obtain registration with OFSTED. Recruit and manage staff & volunteers. Publicise & promotion through local schools. Management of all finances of the after-school club. Write & keep policies up to date according to OFSTED regulations.

Feb 2003 - Aug 2005 Community Regeneration Trust Youth Worker

Main duties: To help develop the youth work program. Plan and run youth clubs and workshops, including healthy eating, photography and creative arts.

Other Full-Time Employment & Gap Years,

Sep 1999 - Aug 2003 Temporary work

HMV, Sales Assistant Northern Rock, Data Input Lloyds TSB, Customer Services Assistant